import { DialogueQuestion } from '@/types/quiz';
// 제주도, 서울, 부산, 중국, 일본, 프랑스, 미국, 스페인, 이탈리아, 태국, 베트남, 싱가포르,
// 왼쪽, 오른쪽
// 올라가다, 올라오다, 내려가다, 내려오다
// 숟가락, 젓가락, 칼, 포크, 나이프
// 밀가루, 쌀, 과자, 카드, 현금,
// 자르다, 시험을 보다, 그림을 그리다, 수업을 듣다, 대화하다, 결제하다,

export const directionMethodQuestions: DialogueQuestion[] = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: '어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip?',
    answer: '제주도로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to Jeju Island.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '제주도', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: '어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip?',
    answer: '중국으로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to China.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '중국', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: '어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip?',
    answer: '프랑스로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to France.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '프랑스', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: '방학에 어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip during the vacation?',
    answer: '방학에 미국으로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to the United States during the vacation.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '방학', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '미국', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: '방학에 어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip during the vacation?',
    answer: '방학에 스페인으로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to Spain during the vacation.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '방학', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '스페인', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: '방학에 어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip during the vacation?',
    answer: '방학에 이탈리아로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to Italy during the vacation.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '방학', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '이탈리아', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: '휴가 때 어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip during the vacation?',
    answer: '휴가 때 태국으로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to Thailand during the vacation.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '휴가', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '때', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '태국', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: '휴가 때 어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip during the vacation?',
    answer: '휴가 때 베트남으로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to Vietnam during the vacation.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '휴가', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '때', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '베트남', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: '휴가 때 어디로 여행을 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on a trip during the vacation?',
    answer: '휴가 때 싱가포르로 여행을 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go on a trip to Singapore during the vacation.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '휴가', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '때', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '싱가포르', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '여행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: '수업이 끝나고 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go after class?',
    answer: '수업이 끝나고 집으로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go home after class.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '수업', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '끝나고', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '집', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: '수업이 끝나고 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go after class?',
    answer: '수업이 끝나고 도서관으로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to the library after class.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '수업', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '끝나고', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '도서관', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: '수업이 끝나고 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go after class?',
    answer: '수업이 끝나고 카페로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to the cafe after class.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '수업', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '끝나고', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '카페', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: '수업이 끝나고 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go after class?',
    answer: '수업이 끝나고 수영장으로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to the swimming pool after class.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '수업', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '끝나고', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '수영장', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: '수업이 끝나고 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go after class?',
    answer: '수업이 끝나고 헬스장으로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to the gym after class.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '수업', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '끝나고', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '헬스장', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: '다음 주에 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go next week?',
    answer: '다음 주에 인도로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to India next week.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '다음', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '주', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '인도', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: '다음 주에 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go next week?',
    answer: '다음 주에 캐나다로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to Canada next week.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '다음', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '주', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '캐나다', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: '다음 달에 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go next month?',
    answer: '다음 달에 미국으로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to the United States next month.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '다음', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '달', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '미국', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: '다음 달에 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go next month?',
    answer: '다음 달에 멕시코로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to Mexico next month.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '다음', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '달', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '멕시코', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: '내년에 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go next year?',
    answer: '내년에 일본으로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to Japan next year.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '내년', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '일본', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: '내년에 어디로 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go next year?',
    answer: '내년에 포르투갈로 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to Portugal next year.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '내년', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '포르투갈', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: '주말에 어디로 놀러 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on weekend?',
    answer: '주말에 부산으로 놀러 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to Busan on weekends.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '주말', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '부산', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '놀러', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: '주말에 어디로 놀러 가요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where do you go on weekend?',
    answer: '주말에 서울로 놀러 가요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I go to Seoul on weekends.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '주말', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '서울', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '놀러', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: '지난 주말에 어디로 놀러 갔어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where did you go on last weekend?',
    answer: '지난 주말에 부산으로 놀러 갔어요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I went to Busan on last weekend.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '지난', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '주말', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '부산', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '놀러', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '갔어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: '지난 주말에 어디로 놀러 갔어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where did you go on last weekend?',
    answer: '지난 주말에 서울로 놀러 갔어요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I went to Seoul on last weekend.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '지난', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '주말', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '서울', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '놀러', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '갔어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: '지난주에 어디로 놀러 갔어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where did you go on last week?',
    answer: '지난주에 제주도로 놀러 갔어요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I went to Jeju Island on last week.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '지난', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '주', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제주도', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '놀러', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '갔어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: '지난주에 어디로 놀러 갔어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where did you go on last week?',
    answer: '지난주에 대구로 놀러 갔어요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I went to Daegu on last week.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '지난', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '주', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '대구', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '놀러', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '갔어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: '영화관이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the movie theater?',
    answer: '7층으로 올라가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Please go up to the 7th floor.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '7층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '올라가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: '식당이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the restaurant?',
    answer: '5층으로 올라가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Please go up to the 5th floor.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '5층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '올라가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: '은행이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the bank?',
    answer: '2층으로 올라가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Please go up to the 2nd floor.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '2층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '올라가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: '화장실이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the bathroom?',
    answer: '3층으로 올라가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Please go up to the 3rd floor.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '3층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '올라가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: '주차장이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the parking lot?',
    answer: '지하 2층으로 내려가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Please go down to the B2 level.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '지하', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '2층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '내려가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: '빵가게가 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the bakery?',
    answer: '지하 1층으로 내려가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Please go down to the B1 level.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '지하', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '1층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '내려가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: '안나 씨, 저는 6층이에요. 지금 몇 층에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Anna, I am on the 3rd floor. Which floor are you on now?',
    answer: '저는 3층에 있어요. 3층으로 내려오세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I am on the 3rd floor. Please come down to the 3rd floor.',
    answerPrefix: '저는 3층에 있어요.',
    answerItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '3층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '내려오세요.' },
    ],
    answerItemsTranslation: 'Please come down to the 3rd floor.',
    answerSuffix: '',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: '안나 씨, 저는 9층이에요. 지금 몇 층에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Anna, I am on the 9th floor. Which floor are you on now?',
    answer: '저는 4층에 있어요. 4층으로 내려오세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I am on the 4th floor. Please come down to the 4th floor.',
    answerPrefix: '저는 4층에 있어요.',
    answerItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '4층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '내려오세요.' },
    ],
    answerItemsTranslation: 'Please come down to the 4th floor.',
    answerSuffix: '',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: '안나 씨, 저는 10층이에요. 지금 몇 층에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Anna, I am on the 10th floor. Which floor are you on now?',
    answer: '저는 6층에 있어요. 6층으로 내려오세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I am on the 6th floor. Please come down to the 6th floor.',
    answerPrefix: '저는 6층에 있어요.',
    answerItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '6층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '내려오세요.' },
    ],
    answerItemsTranslation: 'Please come down to the 6th floor.',
    answerSuffix: '',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: '안나 씨, 저는 11층이에요. 지금 몇 층에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Anna, I am on the 11th floor. Which floor are you on now?',
    answer: '저는 8층에 있어요. 8층으로 내려오세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I am on the 8th floor. Please come down to the 8th floor.',
    answerPrefix: '저는 8층에 있어요.',
    answerItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '8층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '내려오세요.' },
    ],
    answerItemsTranslation: 'Please come down to the 8th floor.',
    answerSuffix: '',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question: '안나 씨, 저는 2층이에요. 지금 몇 층에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Anna, I am on the 2nd floor. Which floor are you on now?',
    answer: '저는 5층에 있어요. 5층으로 올라오세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I am on the 5th floor. Please come up to the 5th floor.',
    answerPrefix: '저는 5층에 있어요.',
    answerItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '5층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '올라오세요.' },
    ],
    answerItemsTranslation: 'Please come up to the 5th floor.',
    answerSuffix: '',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: '안나 씨, 저는 3층이에요. 지금 몇 층에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Anna, I am on the 3rd floor. Which floor are you on now?',
    answer: '저는 6층에 있어요. 6층으로 올라오세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I am on the 6th floor. Please come up to the 6th floor.',
    answerPrefix: '저는 6층에 있어요.',
    answerItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '6층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '올라오세요.' },
    ],
    answerItemsTranslation: 'Please come up to the 6th floor.',
    answerSuffix: '',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: '안나 씨, 저는 4층이에요. 지금 몇 층에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Anna, I am on the 4th floor. Which floor are you on now?',
    answer: '저는 7층에 있어요. 7층으로 올라오세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I am on the 7th floor. Please come up to the 7th floor.',
    answerPrefix: '저는 7층에 있어요.',
    answerItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '7층', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '올라오세요.' },
    ],
    answerItemsTranslation: 'Please come up to the 7th floor.',
    answerSuffix: '',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: '화장실이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the bathroom?',
    answer: '저기 앞에서 오른쪽으로 가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Go straight ahead and turn right.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저기', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '앞', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '오른쪽', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    question: '엘리베이터가 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the elevator?',
    answer: '앞으로 가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Please go straight ahead.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '앞', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question: '편의점이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the convenience store?',
    answer: '저기 앞에서 왼쪽으로 가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Go straight ahead and turn left.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저기', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '앞', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '왼쪽', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question: '편의점이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the convenience store?',
    answer: '저기 은행에서 왼쪽으로 가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Go left at the bank over there.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저기', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '은행', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '왼쪽', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question: '편의점이 어디에 있어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where is the convenience store?',
    answer: '저기 식당에서 오른쪽으로 가세요.',
    answerTranslation: 'Go right at the restaurant over there.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저기', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '식당', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '오른쪽', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '가세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question: '이 과자가 맛있어요. 뭘로 만들었어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'This snack is delicious. What is it made of?',
    answer: '이 과자는 쌀으로 만들었어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['쌀로 이 과자를 만들었어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'This snack is made of rice.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '과자', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '쌀', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '만들었어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    question: '이 빵이 맛있어요. 뭘로 만들었어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'This bread is delicious. What is it made of?',
    answer: '이 빵은 밀가루로 만들었어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['밀가루로 이 빵을 만들었어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'This bread is made of flour.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '빵', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '밀가루', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '만들었어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    question: '요즘 어떻게 일해요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do you work these days?',
    answer: '요즘 집에서 컴퓨터로 일해요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I work at home on my computer these days.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '요즘', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '집', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '컴퓨터', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '일해요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    question: '한국 사람은 어떻게 밥을 먹어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do Korean people eat rice?',
    answer: '한국 사람은 숟가락으로 밥을 먹어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['한국 사람은 밥을 숟가락으로 먹어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'Korean people eat rice with a spoon.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '한국', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '사람', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '숟가락', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '밥', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '7', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '8', content: '먹어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    question: '일본 사람은 어떻게 밥을 먹어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do Japanese people eat rice?',
    answer: '일본 사람은 젓가락으로 밥을 먹어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['일본 사람은 밥을 젓가락으로 먹어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'Japanese people eat rice with chopsticks.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '일본', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '사람', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '젓가락', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '밥', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '7', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '8', content: '먹어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    question: '이 스테이크를 어떻게 먹어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do you eat this steak?',
    answer: '이 스테이크를 포크와 나이프로 드세요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['포크와 나이프로 이 스테이크를 드세요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'Please eat this steak with a fork and a knife.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '스테이크', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '를', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '포크', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '와', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '나이프', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '7', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '8', content: '드세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 51,
    question: '이 사과를 어떻게 잘랐어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you cut this apple?',
    answer: '이 사과를 칼로 잘랐어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['칼로 이 사과를 잘랐어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I cut this apple with a knife.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '사과', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '를', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '칼', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '잘랐어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 52,
    question: '파일을 어디로 보냈어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Where did you send the file?',
    answer: '이메일로 파일을 보냈어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['파일을 이메일로 보냈어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I sent the file by email.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이메일', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '파일', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '보냈어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 53,
    question: '파일을 어떻게 보냈어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you send the file?',
    answer: '핸드폰으로 파일을 보냈어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['파일을 핸드폰으로 보냈어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I sent the file by phone.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '파일', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '보냈어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 54,
    question: '파일을 어떻게 보냈어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you send the file?',
    answer: '컴퓨터로 파일을 보냈어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['파일을 컴퓨터로 보냈어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I sent the file by computer.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '컴퓨터', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '파일', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '보냈어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 55,
    question: '사진을 뭘로 찍었어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What did you take the picture with?',
    answer: '카메라로 사진을 찍었어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['사진을 카메라로 찍었어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I took the picture with a camera.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '카메라', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '사진', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '찍었어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 56,
    question: '사진을 뭘로 찍었어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What did you take the picture with?',
    answer: '핸드폰으로 사진을 찍었어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['사진을 핸드폰으로 찍었어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I took the picture with a phone.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '사진', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '찍었어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 57,
    question: '선생님, 뭘로 이름을 써요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Teacher, what do I write my name with?',
    answer: '펜으로 이름을 쓰세요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['이름을 펜으로 쓰세요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'Please write your name with a pen.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '펜', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '이름', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '쓰세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 58,
    question: '선생님, 뭘로 이름을 써요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Teacher, what do I write my name with?',
    answer: '연필로 이름을 쓰세요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['이름을 연필로 쓰세요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'Please write your name with a pencil.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '연필', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '이름', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '쓰세요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 59,
    question: '지난주에 어떻게 시험을 봤어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you take the test last week?',
    answer: '지난주에 컴퓨터로 시험을 봤어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['지난주에 시험을 컴퓨터로 봤어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I took the test with a computer last week.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '지난주', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '컴퓨터', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '시험', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '봤어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 60,
    question: '이 그림은 어떻게 그렸어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you draw this picture?',
    answer: '이 그림은 연필로 그렸어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['연필로 이 그림을 그렸어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I drew this picture with a pencil.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '그림', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '연필', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '그렸어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 61,
    question: '이 그림은 어떻게 그렸어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you draw this picture?',
    answer: '이 그림은 펜으로 그렸어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['펜으로 이 그림을 그렸어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I drew this picture with a pen.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '그림', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '펜', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '그렸어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 62,
    question: '이 그림은 어떻게 그렸어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you draw this picture?',
    answer: '이 그림은 아이패드로 그렸어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['아이패드로 이 그림을 그렸어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'I drew this picture with an iPad.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '그림', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '아이패드', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '5', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '6', content: '그렸어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 63,
    question: '요즘 사람들은 어떻게 뉴스를 봐요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do people watch the news these days?',
    answer: '요즘은 사람들이 핸드폰으로 뉴스를 봐요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['요즘은 사람들이 뉴스를 핸드폰으로 봐요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'People watch the news on their phones these days.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '요즘', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '사람들', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '뉴스', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '8', content: '를', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '9', content: '봐요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 64,
    question: '요즘 사람들은 어떻게 영화를 봐요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do people watch movies these days?',
    answer: '요즘은 사람들이 핸드폰으로 영화를 봐요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['요즘은 사람들이 영화를 핸드폰으로 봐요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'People watch movies on their phones these days.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '요즘', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '사람들', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '영화', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '8', content: '를', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '9', content: '봐요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 65,
    question: '요즘 사람들은 어떻게 노래를 들어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do people listen to music these days?',
    answer: '요즘은 사람들이 핸드폰으로 노래를 들어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['요즘은 사람들이 노래를 핸드폰으로 들어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'People listen to music on their phones these days.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '요즘', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '사람들', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '노래', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '8', content: '를', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '9', content: '들어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 66,
    question: '한국 사람들은 어떻게 미국 영화를 봐요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do Korean people watch American movies?',
    answer: '한국 사람들은 미국 영화를 한국어로 잘 안 봐요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['한국 사람들은 한국어로 미국 영화를 잘 안 봐요.'],
    answerTranslation: "Korean people don't watch American movies well in Korean.",
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '한국', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '사람들', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '미국', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '영화', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '를', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '한국어', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '8', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '9', content: '잘', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '10', content: '안', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '11', content: '봐요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 67,
    question: '일본 사람들은 어떻게 미국 영화를 봐요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do Japanese people watch American movies?',
    answer: '일본 사람들은 미국 영화를 일본어로 봐요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['일본 사람들은 일본어로 미국 영화를 봐요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'Japanese people watch American movies well in Japanese.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '일본', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '사람들', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '미국', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '영화', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '를', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '일본어', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '8', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '9', content: '봐요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 68,
    question: '학생들은 어떻게 수업을 들어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do students take classes?',
    answer: '학생들이 교실에서 한국어로 수업을 들어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['학생들이 교실에서 수업을 한국어로 들어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'Students are taking classes in Korean in the classroom.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '학생들', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '교실', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '한국어', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '수업', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '8', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '9', content: '들어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 69,
    question: '학생들은 어떻게 수업을 들어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do students take classes?',
    answer: '학생들이 교실에서 영어로 수업을 들어요.',
    alternativeAnswers: ['학생들이 교실에서 수업을 영어로 들어요.'],
    answerTranslation: 'Students are taking classes in English in the classroom.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '학생들', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '교실', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '영어', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '수업', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '8', content: '을', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '9', content: '들어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 70,
    question: '여러분, 교실에서 영어로 말하지 마세요.',
    questionTranslation: "Don't speak English in the classroom, please.",
    answer: '네, 알겠습니다.',
    answerTranslation: 'Yes, I understand.',
    questionPrefix: '여러분, ',
    questionItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '교실', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '영어', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '말하', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '지', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '마세요.', combineWithNext: false },
    ],
    questionItemsTranslation: "Don't speak English in the classroom.",
    questionSuffix: '',
    mode: 'answer-to-question',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 71,
    question: '여러분, 교실에서 한국어로 말하세요.',
    questionTranslation: 'Speak Korean in the classroom, please.',
    answer: '네, 알겠습니다.',
    answerTranslation: 'Yes, I understand.',
    questionPrefix: '여러분, ',
    questionItems: [
      { id: '1', content: '교실', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '에서', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '한국어', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '말하', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '세요.', combineWithNext: false },
    ],
    questionItemsTranslation: 'Speak Korean in the classroom.',
    questionSuffix: '',
    mode: 'answer-to-question',
    items: [],
  },
  {
    id: 72,
    question: '요즘 어떻게 중국어를 공부해요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How do people study Chinese these days?',
    answer: '요즘 중국인 친구하고 중국어로 대화해요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I talk in Chinese with Chinese friends these days.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '요즘', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '중국인', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '친구', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '하고', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '중국어', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '7', content: '대화해요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 73,
    question: '어떻게 결제했어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you pay?',
    answer: '카드로 결제했어요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I paid with a card.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '카드', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '결제했어요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 74,
    question: '어떻게 결제했어요?',
    questionTranslation: 'How did you pay?',
    answer: '현금으로 결제했어요.',
    answerTranslation: 'I paid with cash.',
    items: [
      { id: '1', content: '현금', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '으로', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '결제했어요.' },
    ],
  },
];
